We know it’s good to learn another language.
我们都知道学习另一门语言有很多好处。
It opens doors, makes you more employable, helps you make new friends, and it’s fun too.
它能为你打开机遇之门，让你更具就业竞争力，帮助你结交新朋友，而且学习过程本身也充满乐趣。
But to improve our linguistic skills, many of us have to endure hours of school lessons or evening classes, with our heads buried in textbooks.
但为了提升语言技能，我们很多人不得不忍受很久的课堂教学或夜校课程，埋头于课本之中。
It’s no wonder then that technology appears to be providing a better and more accessible way of learning.
因此，技术似乎能够提供一种更好、更便捷的学习方式，也就不足为奇了。
There is certainly a huge demand for language learning, and having a smartphone means you can have a virtual teacher with you wherever you go.
语言学习的需求无疑非常巨大，而拥有智能手机意味着你无论走到哪里，都能拥有一位虚拟老师。
Many app developers are keen to cash in on the demand, and there are numerous learning apps available – including our own, free, BBC Learning English app!
许多应用程序开发者都急于抓住这一需求商机，市面上涌现出了大量学习类应用——包括我们免费的BBC英语学习应用！
One of many popular apps, Duolingo, offers 91 courses in 30 languages and has more than 300 million users.
多邻国（Duolingo）就是其中一款热门应用，它提供30种语言的91门课程，用户数量已超过3亿。
Some educational apps offer languages not popular enough to be taught at evening classes, or at most universities.
一些教育类应用会提供那些不够热门、无法在夜校或大多数大学里学到的语言课程。
And others offer ‘invented’ language courses in Esperanto, Elvish and Star Trek's Klingon – lessons you might not find in a traditional classroom.
还有一些应用提供世界语、精灵语、《星际迷航》中的克林贡语等“人造语言”课程——这些课程在传统课堂上你可能根本找不到。
Whatever you want to learn, apps allow you to go at your own pace and fit learning around other commitments.
无论你想学什么，应用程序都能让你按照自己的节奏学习，并能在其他事务中灵活安排学习时间。
But they’re not perfect – you might not get your head round the grammar and will lack the peer support you could get in a classroom environment.
但它们并非完美无缺——你可能无法理解语法知识，而且会缺少在课堂环境中能获得的同伴支持。
So, does technology spell the end of traditional classrooms and teachers?
那么，技术是否意味着传统课堂和教师的终结呢？
Guy Baron, head of modern languages at Aberystwyth University, thinks not.
阿伯里斯特威斯大学现代语言学院院长盖伊·巴伦并不这么认为。
He told the BBC that apps should be used alongside classroom methods, not to the exclusion of traditional teaching.
他向英国广播公司表示，应用程序应与课堂教学方法结合使用，而不是排斥传统教学。
And he adds: "The apps are very conversational... they're not designed for degrees, but they could be additional resources."
他还补充道：“这些应用程序非常注重对话交流……它们并非为学位课程设计，但可以作为额外的学习资源。”
Certainly technology is going to help in and outside the classroom.
技术无疑会在课堂内外提供帮助。
But attending a real lesson, facing a real teacher, probably forces you to be more committed.
但参加真实的课程，面对真实的老师，可能会迫使你更加投入。
Motivation can be a problem when using an app.
使用应用程序学习时，动力可能是一个问题。
But if you have a genuine and practical reason to learn another language, you will no doubt stick with it.
但如果你有真实和现实的理由去学习另一门语言，你无疑会坚持下去。